AUSTIN BACK

Personal

Address

944 Whitechapel Rd 29678 Seneca

Phone number

5402711130

Email aback@eagles.bridgewater.edu

Date of birth 28-09-1998

Place of birth Harrisonburg

Gender Male

 ☐ Website austinback.me

⇔ LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-back-772950160/

Interests

- Hiking
- Golf
- Programming
- Computer building and repair
- Reading
- Backyard Telescope

Languages

Arabic

Swedish

I am a current physics Ph.D. student at Clemson University. My current area of research is AMO(Atom I hold a B.S. in Physics from Bridgewater College in which I also earned two minors in computer s performing research or working on programming projects, I enjoy golf, hiking, and playing video gan I love problem-

solving and I believe that is why I am so drawn to physics and programming because they not only al also challenge me. To me, there is no better feeling than seeing a project I've been working on for ho

I believe that one of my biggest character strengths is leadership. When I was younger I spent a lo is where I was able to learn about what it means to be a good leader. I was even accepted to a leader skills I learned there were able to help me later to become the chapter president of my high school's president of the physics club at Bridgewater College.

Work experience

Cart Washer Apr 2016 - Aug 2017

City of Harrisonburg, Harrisonburg

- Washed golf carts
- Cleaned up range balls
- Other various task as needed

Team Member Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Sheetz, Harrisonburg

- Ran cash register
- Prepared food
- Cleaned store

SONIS support Intern

Jenzabar, Harrisonburg

- Helped customers experiencing problems with the SONIS software
- Reported bugs to the dev team
- Educated customers on current and new features
- Created documentation for features

Summer Research Intern Apr 2019 - Jul 2019

Clemson University, Clemson

- Performed research at the Advanced Materials Research Laboratory under Dr. Harell and Dr.
- Wrote final research paper and presented results to my peers
- Extensive use of SEM and TEM

Cashier Apr 2020 - Jul 2020

Lowes, Harrisonburg

- Ran register at various locations
- Cleaned and stocked store
- Helped with closing task

Teaching Assistant Aug 2021 - Present

Clemson University, Clemson

- Ran physics labs
- Graded papers
- Assisted students outside of class with homework and labs

Education and Qualifications

Advanced Diploma Aug 2013 - May 2017

Turner Ashby High School, Bridgewater

Bachelors of Science Aug 2017 - Apr 2021

Brigewater College, Bridgewater • Minor in Computer Science

• Minor in Mathematics

References

References available on request.

Skills

Microsoft Office Suite

Java Programming

Web Design

Machine Learning

Laboratory Skills

Latex